<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-29T20:27:41-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Truth To Light</title><subtitle>John 3:21</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Stairway of Opportunity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/11/12/The-Stairway-of-Opportunity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Stairway of Opportunity" /><published>2023-11-12T12:15:05-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-12T12:15:05-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/12/The-Stairway-of-Opportunity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/11/12/The-Stairway-of-Opportunity.html"><![CDATA[<div class = "content" >

    <!--<img src="stairs.jpg" alt="stairs" height="25%" width="25%" class = "picture" title = "Stairs I saw at a church">-->

    <p>The Stairway of Opportunity is a stairway filled with hurdles and pain, with endless stairs leading to a wooden door. One day, you decide you want to climb the stairs because everyone has been telling you it will lead to success. So you keep climbing and climbing. Your feet bleed from all the climbing, but remember that there will be success in the end. It takes hours to climb, and you wonder if there is even a door up there. You start having doubts, but you cannot go back down because there is nowhere to go back to. You look behind you, and you see blackness. You ask people for help, but there's little they can do. They can only direct you to keep moving forward. Only you can move your legs. Now you forget why you even went up the stairs; didn't your parents force you to go up? Why blame your parents when it was only your choice to go up? Well, the past is the past; you can't do anything about it. You are almost there, and you lose motivation from the climb, and yet you keep going because you are only so close. Everyone is cheering you on so you can open the door. Finally, you take the last step. And you fell from exhaustion. You cry profusely out of joy and tiredness.

    </p>        
    <p>Before you is a big wooden door, that countless people have walked through, and now it's your turn.
         You rise up; Reach for the handle, and…..it won't open. Is it broken? No, it works fine. Is it locked? 
         No, you actually had the key from the beginning of the journey, so you can open it easily.  And yet you dont insert it. 
         Why? You are finished, what are you waiting for? Everyone is counting on you. But you are scared your legs tremble. 
         You dont know what is behind that door. What if there is misery, what if there's nothing behind the door and just a big wall? 
         Or even worse, what if there are even more stairs to do? You want to go back and relieve the memories of when the door did not exist 
         in your mind. Oh, those were the days of no worries, of no leg problems from going up the stairs. They say Curiosity killed the cat, 
         so what if you are going to die from opening the door….. But you will never know. Sure, it might be nothing,, or it might be something.
          But you will never know because you don't have the courage to open the door and move forward.</p>
    
    <p>All these steps are wasted because of your indecisiveness. Yes, they say, “Curiosity killed the cat,’ 
        but they forget the other end of the sentence “The truth brought it back to life.” Regardless of 
        what is behind that door, it is the truth, and you must own it for better or worse. No whining here! we are grown-ups. 
        yes, time went by, but all we can do is own it. Be in control of what we have and are right now. Do not open the door 
        to make your parents or friends proud, but open it to make yourself proud. Say to yourself, “I DID IT,” “I CONQUERED MY FEAR,” or
         “THIS HARD WORK PAID OFF FOR BETTER OR FOR WORSE”. You insert the key. You turn the knob. You open the door and…
    </p>

    <p style = "text-align: center">The End</p>

    <!--
    <p>Thank you for reading our post. 
        Stay updated on new content by subscribing to our newsletter through the <a href="contact.html">Contact Form</a>. 
        We value your insights, so don't hesitate to share your thoughts in the comments. 
        I am always looking for inquires, so if you have an idea of what I should write next please 
        leave a comment in the contact form. </p>
-->
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A super brief history of the church</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/15/A-super-brief-history-of-the-church.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A super brief history of the church" /><published>2023-08-15T13:15:05-04:00</published><updated>2023-08-15T13:15:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/08/15/A-super-brief-history-of-the-church</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/08/15/A-super-brief-history-of-the-church.html"><![CDATA[<div class = "content" >

    <h3>In the beginning</h3>
    <p>In The beginning, God made man and had a close relationship with man. However, sin entered the world, and man and God's relationship was broken since man disobeyed God. Despised of this, God remained faithful and promised a Savior that could help restore the relationship and be reunited as before</p>
    
    <h3>The Old Covenant</h3>
    <p>Throughout history, God revealed Himself with the help of prophets and made covenants with Humans. His foundation lay with the Israelites, the chosen people. For the coming of the Messiah, God desired people to be prepared so that his plan for salvation could gradually unfold. Despite numerous rebellions, God's mercy prevailed, accepting offerings for sins. However, these sacrifices were insufficient, necessitating the coming of the Messiah.</p>
    
    <h3>The New Covenant</h3>
    <p>In Nazareth, a young woman named Mary received a visitation from an angel announcing that Mary was chosen by God to bear the son of God, the long-awaited Messiah and Savior. Mary accepted the will of God, and Jesus grew to be a great prophet and leader. He performed many miracles and proclaimed the coming of the kingdom of God and that people must repent to have eternal life. Jesus also announced the New Covenant that would be established through His death. </p>
    
    <h3>Establishing the church </h3>
    <p>Jesus, through his earthly life, established what is known now as the catholic church. Jesus appointed the apostles as the church's foundation, giving them authority to teach, govern and sanctify in his name. Peter was also given the keys to the kingdom and became vicar of Christ. Furthermore, he gave the apostles authority to forgive sins and consecrate the Eucharist, establishing them as priests.In the end, he got Crucified to save humanity's life from sin. At Pentecost, Jesus ascended, and the holy spirit descended to the apostles, making this the birthday of the church.</p>
    
    <h3>Church Growth and Challenges</h3>
    <p>Over time, the Christian Church grew in numbers and developed its doctrines, rooted in the teachings of Jesus. Initially, Christians worshipped in secret since Christianity was illegal.  Luckily in the 4th century, Emperor Constantine's legalization of Christianity empowered the Church to evangelize openly and grow in numbers. It's important to note that Constantine didn't create the Catholic Church; he simply legalized it.
    </p>
    <p>Over time Councils were convened to establish doctrine, but challenges arose. A notable division occurred in 1054, known as the Great Schism, splitting Christianity into East and West over disagreements on the "filioque" clause and papal authority.
    </p>
    <p>Around the 16th century, Protestant Reformation emerged. This movement, a response to disagreement with Catholic Church teachings with papal authority and to corruption of indulgences, led to various Protestant denominations sprouting.</p>

    <h3>Counter-Reformation and Ongoing Development</h3>
    <p>The 16th Century went into a period called the Post-Reformation, where the church initiated councils to the Catholic Church initiated the Counter-Reformation to address issues addressed in the protestant reformation and also strengthen its doctrinal teachings. Throughout history, The church continues evolving, acknowledging past errors. Even in modern times, challenges persist, including the sexual abuse scandal. However, due to all these challenges, the church doesn't back down and keeps moving forward, spreading the word and keeping the teachings of Jesus alive. </p>

    <hr>

</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life is a Journey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/28/Life-is-a-Journey.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life is a Journey" /><published>2023-07-28T13:15:05-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-28T13:15:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/28/Life-is-a-Journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/28/Life-is-a-Journey.html"><![CDATA[<div>
  <!--<h1 class = "about" style = "text-align: center">Life is a Journey</h1>
  <img src="wanderer.jpg" alt="wanderer" height="25%" width="25%" class = "picture" title = "Wanderer above the Sea of Fog By Caspar David Friedrich"> -->

  
  <p>We are fallen beings, and our destination is to Go to Heaven by Following the Truth</p>
  <p> According to the Catechism of the Catholic Church, the Truth is found in Christ. 
      He is "<i>Full of grace and truth, he came as the "light of the world," he is the Truth. 
      "Whoever believes in me may not remain in darkness." The disciple of Jesus continues in his word to know "the truth [that] 
      will make you free," and that sanctifies.</i>"(CCC 2466).</p>
  <p>It is essential we dont stray away from the Truth or we fall from Darkeness. 
      Because we are fallen beings, temptation creeps around the corner waiting for us to fall. In life, we have distractions,  
      making us unable to move forward and see the light. With the help of the Holy Spirit, we can move forward. 
      With the help of others in the faith, we can move forward. </p>

  <h3><i>My Odyssey</i> by Calvin</h3>
  <pre class="odyssey">
  I open my eyes 
  and the birds are singing in harmony.
  As I drift through the lakes of clouds,
  I meet the little siren 
  who offers me an apple.
  I must refuse and go forth !!
  Poseidon looks at me gaily 
  but his brothers do not.
  Zephyrus blows me toward home
  So I tune a gift for him as an homage
  I finally came and greeted my home 
  And I thank those who have helped me find the path of my odyssey.
  </pre>

</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>